A Guide to the Douglas Southall Freeman Papers 1900-1955
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Lee, R.E.; Farewell Order No. 9, [Discussions of] 1947 (Box 9)
- Lee, Robert E. [Mrs.] 1939 (Box 9)
- "Lee's Lieutenants" by D.F. Freeman ca. 1944 (Box 9)
- Letters, Historical (Including Typed Transcripts) 1804-1882, n.d. (Box 9)
- Libraries 1922-1938 (Box 9)
- Library of Congress 1942 (Box 9)
- Lincoln, A. 1946 (Box 9)
- Lindbergh, C.A. 1932-1941, n.d. (Box 9)
- Linguistic Atlas n.d. (Box 9)
- Lippmann, Walter 1933 (Box 9)
- Liquor Control 1933-1944 (Box 9)
- Literary Fund, Virginia 1944 (Box 9)
- Little Sisters of the Poor 1943 (Box 9)
- Locarno Treaty 1925 (Box 9)
- Locksmiths 1940 (Box 9)
- London Naval Treaty 1930 (Box 9)
- Longevity 1922, 1948 (Box 9)
- Lynchburg 1936 (Box 9)
- MacArthur, Gen. Douglas 1931-1952 (Box 9)
- Machines, Political 1912 (Box 9)
- Magna Carta 1939 (Box 9)
- Malta 1940, 1942 (Box 9)
- Manchuria 1931-1941 (Box 9)
- Manganese 1931 (Box 9)
- Manning, Bishop ca. 1930 (Box 9)
- Mao-Tse Tung 1950 (Box 10)
- Map, Blackstone, Virginia; annotated 1939
- Map, Richmond (a copy) 1835
- Maps 1937-1942 (Box 10)
- Marines 1943 (Box 10)
- Marriages 1932-1941 (Box 10)
- Marshall, Alfred 1915 (Box 10)
- Marshall, Gen. Geo. C. 1943, 1945 (Box 10)
- Marshall, John (Typed Transcript) 1890 (Box 10)
- Massaponax Baptist Church 1938 (Box 10)
- Massie-Walke (Typed Transcripts of Correspondence) 1923 (Box 10)
- Master Farmers 1930 (Box 10)
- Maury, Matthew Fontaine (Typed Transcript) 1850, 1920 (Box 10)
- McCarthy, Sen. Jos. 1951-1954 (Box 10)
- McCue, E.O. 1950 (Box 10)
- Mechanics Institute ca. 1937 (Box 10)
- Medicine, Socalized 1955, n.d. (Box 10)
- Mental Hygiene 1917-1931 (Box 10)
- Michie Tavern, Charlottesville 1940 (Box 10)
- Milk ca. 1921-1951 (Box 10)
- Mill Brook, Spotsylvania County n.d. (Box 10)
- Minerals, Virginia 1948 (Box 10)
- Missouri Valley 1945-1953 (Box 10)
- Mitchell, John, Jr. 1922, 1927 (Box 10)
- Monticello 1923 (Box 10)
- Moore, R. Walton 1926 (Box 10)
- Mosby, John S. 1902 (Box 10)
- Mosque, Richmond 1938 (Box 10)
- Motion Pictures n.d. (Box 10)
- Motion Picture Censorship 1938 (Box 10)
- Munford, Mrs. B.B. 1922-1950, n.d. (Box 10)
- Murray, "Alfalfa Bill" 1931 (Box 10)
- Muscle Shoals 1924-1933, n.d. (Box 10)
- Music and Musicians 1916-1933, n.d. (Box 10)
- National Bankrupcy ca. 1948-1952, n.d. (Box 10)
- National Defense 1940-1951 (Box 10)
- National Defense, Virginia 1940 (Box 10)
- National Guard 1920-1933 (Box 10)
- National Economy League 1932-1933 (Box 10)
- National Industrial Recovery Act 1933 (Box 10)
- National Labor Relations Board 1950 (Box 10)
- National Theatre 1924, n.d. (Box 10)
- National Youth Administration 1941 (Box 10)
- Navies 1928-1942 (Box 10)
- Nazis 1934 (Box 10)
- Netherlands ca. 1940 (Box 10)
- Neutrality 1937-ca. 1940, n.d. (Box 10)
- New Britain Herald(Connecticut) 1953 (Box 10)
- New Deal 1935-1943 (Box 10)
- New York City ca. 1928-ca. 1938, n.d. (Box 10)
- New Zealand n.d. (Box 11)
- News Leader Library (Bound files in, complied by Dr. Cappon) n.d. (Box 11)
- Newspaper Build 1934, 1940 (Box 11)
- Newspapers 1923-1948, n.d. (Box 11)
- Newsprint n.d. (Box 11)
- Niemoeller, Rev. Martin 1940, 1945 (Box 11)
- Nicaragua 1927-1930, n.d. (Box 11)
- Nixon, Richard M. 1952, n.d. (Box 11)
- Noises 1933, n.d. (Box 11)
- Noland, L.U. 1944 (Box 11)
- Norfolk n.d. (Box 11)
- Norfolk and Western (Railway) 1938 (Box 11)
- North Atlantic Pact 1949-1955 (Box 11)
- North Carolina n.d. (Box 11)
- North Dakota 1938 (Box 11)
- Northern Neck Association 1926 (Box 11)
- Norway 1940, 1941 (Box 11)
- Noyes, Clara Dutton 1933 (Box 11)
- Nurses 1925-1945 (Box 11)
- Nutrition n.d. (Box 11)
- Obici, A. 1930 (Box 11)
- Oceans 1931 (Box 11)
- Office Buildings, State of Va. 1947 (Box 11)
- Oil ca. 1922-1948, n.d. (Box 11)
- "O.K." (origin of) 1934 (Box 11)
- Old Age Pensions 1929 (Box 11)
- Old Buildings, Richmond 1929, 1937, n.d. (Box 11)
- Oleomargerine 1939-ca. 1950, n.d. (Box 11)
- Olympic Games 1935 (Box 11)
- OPA 1944, 1945 (Box 11)
- OPA, Virginia 1944 (Box 11)
- Open Shop 1930 (Box 11)
- Orchestra (Richmond) 1932, 1934, n.d. (Box 11)
- Osborne, E.A. n.d. (Box 11)
- Outlawing of War 1927 (Box 11)
- Oxford Group 1938-1943 (Box 11)
- Oysters ca. 1917-1953 (Box 11)
- Painting ca. 1941 (Box 11)
- Palestine 1924-1948, n.d. (Box 11)
- Panama Canal 1931 (Box 11)
- Pan America 1951 (Box 11)
- Pan American News 1940 (Box 11)
- Panics 1931, 1932 (Box 11)
- Paper 1943 (Box 11)
- Paper, Newsprint 1918-1920, n.d. (Box 11)
- Parke, Col. Daniel ca. 1937 (Box 11)
- Parking Meters 1936-1939 (Box 11)
- Parks 1949, n.d. (Box 12)
- Payne, Judge J.B. 1925 (Box 12)
- Peace 1924-1943 (Box 12)
- Peace Conference 1919 (Box 12)
- Peace, The Defeat of; News Leader Editorials 1938, 1939 (Box 12)
- Peace Terms, Europe 1945 (Box 12)
- Peace Terms, Japan 1945 (Box 12)
- Peace Treaties 1946, 1947 (Box 12)
- Pearl Harbor 1944 (Box 12)
- Peddlers n.d. (Box 12)
- Peery, Geo. 1934 (Box 12)
- Pendleton, Col. Hunter 1932 (Box 12)
- Penitentiary, State 1931-1936 (Box 12)
- Pensions 1925-1935, n.d. (Box 12)
- Perkins, Malcolm W. 1931 (Box 12)
- Petain, Gen F. 1917 (Box 12)
- Petersburg, Va. 1873, 1923-1932, n.d. (Box 12)
- Phi Beta Kappa 1926-1942 (Box 12)
- Philharmonic Symphony 1945 (Box 12)
- Philippines 1919-1959, n.d. (Box 12)
- Phonetics n.d. (Box 12)
- Pickett, Camp 1939, 1944 (Box 12)
- Pius XII, Pope 1943 (Box 12)
- "Planet, the Richmond" 1932 (Box 12)
- Planning 1937, 1938 (Box 12)
- Pollard, John Garland 1920-1938 (Box 12)
- Polls 1936 (Box 12)
- Population 1940-1950 (Box 12)
- Porter, John Luke, C.S.N. 1924 (Box 12)
- Portugal 1937 (Box 12)
- Potato Bugs 1950 (Box 12)
- Potsdam Conference 1945 (Box 12)
- Power ca. 1928-1952 (Box 12)
- Presbyterians 1925-1940, n.d. (Box 12)
- Presidental Election of 1928 1928, n.d. (Box 12)
- Presidental Election of 1944 1944 (Box 12)
- Presidental Election of 1948 1948 (Box 12)
- Presidental Election of 1952 1952, n.d. (Box 12)
- President's Comission, Higher Education 1946 (Box 12)
- Preventorium, Teachers 1929 (Box 12)
- Prices 1920-1934 (Box 12)
- Price Indexes ca. 1940 (Box 12)
- Primary 1926 (Box 12)
- Prisons 1937 (Box 12)
- Prison Farms n.d. (Box 12)
- Processing Tax 1935 (Box 12)
- Profit 1919-1920 (Box 12)
- Prohibition (Including Typed Transcript) 1885, 1918-1935, n.d. (Box 12)
- Property Survey 1934 (Box 13)
- Proportional Representation 1930 (Box 13)
- Psychiatry 1934 (Box 13)
- Public Health, Richmond 1945 (Box 13)
- Public Schools 1929-1950 (Box 13)
- Public Schools, Richmond 1941-1945, n.d. (Box 13)
- Public School Segregation 1951 (Box 12)
- Public Works Administration, Virginia 1936 (Box 13)
- Pulitzer Prizes n.d. (Box 13)
- Pullman Company 1931 (Box 13)
- Purchasing Agent, Richmond 1944 (Box 13)
- Questionnaires 1931 (Box 13)
- Quiz Kids 1943 (Box 13)
- R.F. and P. Railroad 1930, 1953 (Box 13)
- Racial Bills 1925 (Box 13)
- Racing 1934 (Box 13)
- Radio 1927-1950, n.d. (Box 13)
- Railroads 1916-1925, n.d. (Box 13)
- Railroads 1931-1935 (Box 13)
- Rationing 1942, 1943 (Box 13)
- Rayon 1936 (Box 13)
- Real Estate 1933 (Box 13)
- Reavis Case 1927 (Box 13)
- Reconciliation Pact n.d. (Box 13)
- Reconstruction Finance Corporation 1932-1951 (Box 13)
- Red Cross 1919-1953, n.d. (Box 13)
- Reeder, Sherwood ca. 1949 (Box 13)
- Refugees ca. 1939, 1940 (Box 13)
- Relief 1932-1951, n.d. (Box 13)
- Relief, Foreign 1947 (Box 13)
- Relics and Souvenirs 1877-1924 (Box 13)
- Religion 1936, n.d. (Box 13)
- Rents 1950 (Box 13)
- Republican Party 1921, 1944 (Box 13)
- Research 1923 (Box 13)
- Retail Distribution 1931 (Box 13)
- Retreat for the Sick ca. 1951-1953, n.d. (Box 13)
- Revolution, American (Photostat of document dated 1833 with endorsement 1783) 1833, 1873 (Box 13)
- Rhodes Scholarships 1936, 1939 (Box 13)
- Richmond ca. 1908-1927, n.d. (Box 13)
- Richmond Assets 1919-1920 (Box 13)
- Richmond Chamber of Commerce 1925 (Box 13)
- Richmond First Club 1940-1941 (Box 13)
- Richmond - Graphs of Growth in Population, Banks, etc. 1928 (Box 13)
- Richmond, Miscellaneous Reports 1935-1936 (Box 13)
- Richmond, Port of 1950, n.d. (Box 13)
- Richmond Professional Institute 1945 (Box 13)
- Richmond, University of 1924-1942 (Box 14)
- "Rights of Man" 1941 (Box 14)
- Riverlake Package 1949-1951 (Box 14)
- Roads ca. 1914-1950, n.d. (Box 14)
- Roads, Virginia 1919-1952, n.d. (Box 14)
- Rock Dusting 1932 (Box 14)
- Rockefeller Foundation 1943-1945 (Box 14)
- Rolfe, John (a print) n.d. (Box 14)
- Roosevelt, Franklin D. 1935-1942, n.d. (Box 14)
- Rosenwald Fund 1943 (Box 14)
- Rubber 1931-1943, n.d. (Box 14)
- Rudd, W.F. ca. 1934 (Box 14)
- Rumely, Dr. E.A. 1950-1951 (Box 14)
- Rural Electrification 1942, 1947 (Box 14)
- Rural Life 1941 (Box 14)
- Russia 1919-1955, n.d. (Box 14)
- St. Lawrence River 1941-1951 (Box 14)
- St. Paul's Church 1945 (Box 14)
- St. Paul's Normal and Industrial School 1937 (Box 14)
- Saito, Horosh 1934 (Box 14)
- Salaries, Richmond 1950 (Box 14)
- Sales Tax 1947-1950, n.d. (Box 14)
- Salmon Fisheries 1920 (Box 14)
- Salvage 1942, n.d. (Box 14)
- Salvation Army 1920-1945, n.d. (Box 14)
- Sam Browne Belt 1939 (Box 14)
- Sandino, "General" n.d. (Box 14)
- Sanger, Dr. W.T. 1950 (Box 14)
- Satayana, George 1944 (Box 14)
- Sawyer-Ferguson-Walker Co. 1943 (Box 14)
- Scheibert, Major I. 1942 (Box 14)
- Schools, Richmond (including Typed Transcript) 1900, 1917-1920, n.d. (Box 14)
- Schuman Plan 1950 (Box 14)
- Seal of Virginia 1935 (Box 14)
- Second Baptist Church ca. 1920, n.d. (Box 14)
- Second District Virginia 1938 (Box 14)
- Second Presbyterian Church of the South 1938 (Box 14)
- Securities Exchange Comission 1940 (Box 14)
- Senate Committee on Economy 1933 (Box 14)
- Senate-John Hay's Opinion 1919 (Box 14)
- Senators, Virginia n.d. (Box 14)
- Serbia (by Dr. Rosalie Slaughter Morton) ca. 1917 (Box 14)
- Seven Days' Battles, 1862 1922 (Box 15)
- Sewage Disposal 1935 (Box 15)
- Shelton-Lacy Case 1925 (Box 15)
- Shenandoah, Confederate Cruiser 1937 (Box 15)
- Shenandoah National Park 1924-1934, n.d. (Box 15)
- Sherman Anti-Trust Law 1921 (Box 15)
- Ship Subsidy 1922-1934 (Box 15)
- Shippen Document (Typewritten Copy) 1864 (Box 15)
- Shipwrecks n.d. (Box 15)
- Shockoe Cemetery n.d. (Box 15)
- Shriver, Alfred Jenkins 1935 (Box 15)
- Siberia 1942 (Box 15)
- Silver 1931-1944 (Box 15)
- Silver shirts ca. 1933 (Box 15)
- Simplification, State Government 1923 (Box 15)
- Singapore 1941 (Box 15)
- Slavery 1930 (Box 15)
- Slemp, Bascom 1931 (Box 15)
- Small Loans ca. 1922-1924 (Box 15)
- Smith, Gerald L. K. 1942, 1944 (Box 15)
- Smith, John, Capt. n.d. (Box 15)
- Smithey, Major Marvin 1923 (Box 15)
- Smoke 1948, n.d. (Box 15)
- Smuts, Gen. 1917-1942 (Box 15)
- Snakes 1933 (Box 15)
- Snows 1939 (Box 15)
- Social Agencies, Council of 1933 (Box 15)
- Social Credit 1940 (Box 15)
- Social Security 1936-1951 (Box 15)
- Society of American Historians 1938-1943, n.d. (Box 15)
- Social Erosion 1934, n.d. (Box 15)
- Soldiers' Bonus 1922-1935 (Box 15)
- Soldiers' Home 1941 (Box 15)
- Southern College 1936 (Box 15)
- "Southern Churchman" 1935 (Box 15)
- Southern Medical Association 1933 (Box 15)
- Southern Industry 1951-1952 (Box 15)
- Southern Newspapers Publishers' Association 1941 (Box 15)
- Souvenirs 1840-1953 (Box 15)
- Spain 1931-1951 (Box 15)
- Speed Limits 1952 (Box 15)
- Sparkmen, John 1952 (Box 15)
- Speidal, Dr. C. C. n.d. (Box 15)
- Spelling 1940-1953 (Box 15)
- Stalin, Joseph 1932-1952 (Box 15)
- Staples, Abram P. ca. 1950, n.d. (Box 15)
- Stassen, Harold E. 1950 (Box 15)
- State Board of Health n.d. (Box 15)
- State Fair 1943 (Box 15)
- States' Finances 1923-1935 (Box 15)
- State Highway 1920-1922, n.d. (Box 15)
- State Library 1924-1947, n.d. (Box 15)
- State Policy 1952 (Box 15)
- Steel 1937-1953 (Box 15)
- Stephens, Alexander H. (Typed Copies) 1866, 1871, n.d. (Box 15)
- Sterilization 1933 (Box 15)
- Stock Market 1920-1394 (Box 15)
- Stone and Webster Company ca. 1928 (Box 15)
- Stratford 1929-1952 (Box 15)
- Stratosphere ca. 1934 (Box 16)
- Street Cars 1920-1921 (Box 16)
- Streets n.d. (Box 16)
- Streets, Richmond ca. 1923-1928, n.d. (Box 16)
- Strikes 1919-1941 (Box 16)
- Stuart, Charles E. 1933 (Box 15)
- Stuart, Charles E. of Stratford, Va. 1927 (Box 16)
- Stuart, H.C. n.d. (Box 16)
- Stuart, J.E.B. (Typewritten Copy) 1863, 1935, n.d. (Box 16)
- Stuart's Ride Around McClellan n.d. (Box 16)
- Student Volunteer Convention 1923 (Box 16)
- Submarines 1917 (Box 16)
- Subsidies 1943 (Box 16)
- Sugar 1918-1946, n.d. (Box 16)
- Sulfridge, Miss E.W. ca. 1936-1938, n.d. (Box 16)
- Sumners, Hatton W. 1938 (Box 16)
- Sunday Closing 1919, 1921, n.d. (Box 16)
- Supreme Court 1935-1955, n.d. (Box 16)
- Supreme Court, Virginia 1944 (Box 16)
- Swem, E.G. 1919-1923 (Box 16)
- Swords, Samurai 1946 (Box 16)
- Taft, Robert A. 1951-1952 (Box 16)
- Talbolt, Harold E. 1955 (Box 16)
- Tariff 1922-1932, n.d. (Box 16)
- Tariff, Editorials, "Richmond News Leader" 1930, 1932 (Box 16)
- Tariff, Reciprocal 1943 (Box 16)
- Taxation 1929-1951, n.d. (Box 16)
- Taxation, States 1951 (Box 16)
- Taylor Case (George E. Taylor) 1922-1924, n.d. (Box 16)
- Teachers' Pay 1920-1921, n.d. (Box 16)
- Technocracy 1932 (Box 16)
- Technotax 1934 (Box 16)
- Telephones 1926-1952 (Box 16)
- Telephones 1926-1952 (Box 16)
- Tetley, Gerard n.d. (Box 16)
- Theatre 1937-1946, n.d. (Box 16)
- Theatre, Civic 1929-1930 (Box 16)
- Thompson, Shadrack (Case) 1932-1933 (Box 16)
- Thoroughfare Gap 1946 (Box 16)
- Tibet 1950 (Box 16)
- Tidewater Oil 1952 (Box 16)
- Tidelands 1949-1951 (Box 17)
- Times Dispatch, Richmond 1921-1934, n.d. (Box 17)
- Tires ca. 1935, 1945 (Box 17)
- Tobacco 1929-1943 (Box 17)
- Tobacco Growers' Co-op 1924-1926 (Box 17)
- Tompkins, Capt. Sally 1936 (Box 17)
- Tornado (Richmond) 1951 (Box 17)
- Towns, Virginia 1950 (Box 17)
- Toys 1931 (Box 17)
- Trade Barriers 1939 (Box 17)
- Trade Unions 1931 (Box 17)
- Traffic 1930-1950 (Box 17)
- Traffic, Richmond 1951 (Box 17)
- Transatlantic Flights 1941 (Box 17)
- Travel 1930 (Box 17)
- Treasury, Secretaries of U.S. 1934 (Box 17)
- Treaties 1945, 1947 (Box 17)
- Tredegar Iron Works 1943 (Box 17)
- Trinkle, Gov E. Lee 1924-1925, n.d. (Box 17)
- Trucks 1936-1951, n.d. (Box 17)
- Truman-Attlee Conference 1950 (Box 17)
- Tuberculosis 1929, 1954 (Box 17)
- Turkey 1933 (Box 17)
- Turkeys 1931, 1933 (Box 17)
- Tuskegee Institute 1938 (Box 17)
- Type 1946 (Box 17)
- Typographical Union 1933 (Box 17)
- Tyus, L.W. 1943 (Box 17)
- Unemployment 1929 (Box 17)
- Unemployment Compensation Comission 1940 (Box 17)
- Unemployed Council 1933 (Box 17)
- "Union Now" 1939-1943, n.d. (Box 17)
- United Service Organization 1945-1946 (Box 17)
- Universal Military Training 1951-1952, n.d. (Box 17)
- Venereal Disease 1919, n.d. (Box 17)
- Veterans Administration 1924-1951 (Box 17)
- Vicksburg 1925 (Box 17)
- Virgin Islands 1931 (Box 17)
- Virginia 1864, 1925-1926, n.d. (Box 17)
- Virginia Beach 1938 (Box 17)
- "Virginia (Merrimack), Confederate States Ship" 1936 (Box 17)
- Virginia Electric and Power Company 1917-1946, n.d. (Box 17)
- Virginia Historical Pageant Association 1921-1922, n.d. (Box 18)
- Virginia Historical Society 1922, n.d. (Box 18)
- Virginia Military Institute (VMI) 1918-1944, n.d. (Box 18)
- Virginia Normal and Industrial Institute 1918 (Box 18)
- Virginia Polytechnic Institute (VPI) 1919-1944 (Box 18)
- Virginia Public Service Company 1938 (Box 18)
- Virginia State Chamber of Commerce 1924-1927, n.d. (Box 18)
- Virginia Union University 1936 (Box 18)
- Virginia War History Comission 1919-1921, n.d. (Box 18)
- Virginia - Conditions and Possibilities 1919, 1923 (Box 18)
- Vital Statistics 1920-1928 (Box 18)
- Vocational Education 1944 (Box 18)
- Volcanoes ca. 1930 (Box 18)
- Voting 1918-1924, 1946 (Box 18)
- Wages 1919-1943, n.d. (Box 18)
- Wages and Hours Bill 1938 (Box 18)
- Wagner Act 1937 (Box 18)
- Walker, Dugald Stewart 1918 (Box 18)
- Wallace, Henry A. 1946-1951 (Box 18)
- Walton, Jr., C.C. 1927, n.d. (Box 18)
- War 1930-1931 (Box 18)
- War of 1939 1930-1946, n.d. (Box 18)
- War - AP Flimsies of Sept. 1, 1939 1939 (Box 18)
- War Atrocities 1929 (Box 18)
- War Contracts 1942-1943 (Box 18)
- War Costs 1925 (Box 18)
- War-General Policies 1916-1918, n.d. (Box 18)
- War With Germany 1927 (Box 18)
- War Graves ca. 1938 (Box 18)
- War Information Series 1918 (Box 18)
- War Insurance 1917-1919 (Box 18)
- War Letters 1863, 1940-1945, n.d. (Box 18)
- War Libraries 1917 (Box 18)
- War Loans 1943 (Box 18)
- War Losses 1917-1925 (Box 18)
- War Memorials 1919-1921, n.d. (Box 18)
- War, Outlawing of 1928 (Box 19)
- War Production 1942 (Box 19)
- War Relief 1917-1918, 1941, n.d. (Box 19)
- War - West - 1917 1917 (Box 19)
- War Work Council, YMCA 1917-1918 (Box 19)
- Warsaw, Poland 1943 (Box 19)
- Warwick, Virginia 1935 (Box 19)
- Washington, Booker T. 1952 (Box 19)
- Washington Cathedral 1938 (Box 19)
- Washington, DC 1947 (Box 19)
- Washington, George 1922, 1935 (Box 19)
- Washington State ca. 1940 (Box 19)
- Water 1917 (Box 19)
- Water Control 1946-1949, n.d. (Box 19)
- Water Power 1947 (Box 19)
- Water Supply 1931-1945 (Box 19)
- Wavel, Gen. Sir Archibald P. 1942 (Box 19)
- Weather, Reports (General and Special) 1924-1948, n.d. (Box 19)
- Webb Export Law 1931 (Box 19)
- Weckert, John C. (Managing Ed. for "The Stars and Bars") 1926 (Box 19)
- Wedemeyer Report 1951 (Box 19)
- Weeds 1950 (Box 19)
- West Point Military Academy 1951 (Box 19)
- Western Union 1919-1952, n.d. (Box 19)
- Westhampton College n.d. (Box 19)
- Whaling 1939 (Box 19)
- Wheat 1930 (Box 19)
- Wheeler, Sen. Burton K. 1941 (Box 19)
- White, Harry Dexter 1953 (Box 19)
- William Allen White Committee 1918, 1940-1941, 2 folders (Box 19)
- William Byrd Community House 1920-1924 (Box 19)
- William Hohenzollern, Kaiser 1900, 1917 (Box 19)
- Williamsburg, Virginia 1935-1938 (Box 19)
- Williamstown Institute 1926 (Box 19)
- Willkie, Wendell 1946 (Box 19)
- Willkie, Wendell 1940-1942 (Box 19)
- Wilmer Eye Institute 1931 (Box 19)
- Wilson, C.E. 1953 (Box 19)
- Wilson, Woodrow 1916-1926, n.d.
- Winchester Star 1923 (Box 19)
- Windischgraetz, Prince Ludwig 1921 (Box 19)
- Wines 1934-1945, n.d. (Box 19)
- Witz, Captain 1919 (Box 19)
- Wise, Jennings C. 1918-1928, n.d. (Box 19)
- Women 1933, n.d. (Box 19)
- Women in Business 1936-1937 (Box 20)
- Woman's Suffrage 1920-1923 (Box 20)
- Women In Production Service (WIPS) 1943 (Box 20)
- Women's Army Corps, U.S. 1944, n.d. (Box 20)
- Women's Work Today 1926-1928, n.d. (Box 20)
- Woodfill, Samuel 1921 (Box 20)
- Wool 1941 (Box 20)
- Words (Excerpts "Lorna Doone," 1673) n.d. (Box 20)
- Work Relief 1935 (Box 20)
- Workmen's Compensation Law 1919 (Box 20)
- World Court 1923-1932, n.d. (Box 20)
- World Economic conference 1933 (Box 20)
- World Trade Club 1919, n.d. (Box 20)
- Wright Case 1933 (Box 20)
- Wyatt, Wm. W. 1925 (Box 20)
- Wysor, R.J. 1937 (Box 20)
- Yacht Races n.d. (Box 20)
- YMCA 1941, n.d. (Box 20)
- Yorktown, Va. 1923-1925, n.d. (Box 20)
- Young, Owen J. 1931 (Box 20)
- Youth 1937-1945, n.d. (Box 20)
- Youth Congress 1940-1941, n.d. (Box 20)
- Yugoslavia 1931-1955, n.d. (Box 20)
- YWCA 1918-1923, n.d. (Box 20)
- Zionism 1943 (Box 20)
- Zoning 1926-1946 (Box 20)